Michael King Any Town, NY 99999 999-999-9999

email@yahoo.comt http://www.linkedin.com/in/Profile

Summary

Business / Data Analyst: Extensive experience including applications development, operations and technical support. Areas of knowledge cover Staffing, Payroll, Tax, Benefits, Stock, and Mergers & Acquisitions on a world wide scale.

Technical Skills

SQL, SQR, MS Access, Visio, PeopleSoft Query, PeopleSoft Application Designer, Microsoft Project, TOAD, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook, COGNOS, iCIMS, EDW, Data Modeling, Process Modeling, Human Dynamics, Oracle, People Code, People Tools, PeopleSoft Benefits, PeopleSoft Payroll, Oracle, SQL Server 5.0, SharePoint, Mercury Quality Center, JAD, SAP (AT&A)

Professional Experience

ABC Inc. Any Town, NY Data Analyst

01/2008 - 01/2009

- Responsible for leading software testing, troubleshooting, and implementation.
- Support end-users, company-wide to resolve database/software issues utilizing remote desktop tools.
- Database recovery and subsequent problem resolution.
- Meet with customers to determine their needs, gather and document requirements, communicate with customers throughout the development project to manage customer expectations, resolve issues, and provide project status.
- Coordinates project development and implementation activities.
- Query Reports using Access and SQL.

XYZ Corp. Any Town, NY

05/2007 - 07/2007

Data Analyst

- Developed data validation system
- Prepared plans for sample size calculations and sampling design.

BCD Inc. Any Town, NY

04/1984 - 11/2006

Data Analyst

- Relating customer data from multiple internal and external source systems (like Channels, Siebel, ERP, WIPS) into a central, consolidated company-wide customer database in a timely manner. Offered input to improve customer data processing, and informed team lead about company hierarchy issues during staff meetings.
- Worked autonomously within a team of Data Analysts, to analyze, review, update, edit, clean, translate, and ensure accuracy of customer data.
- Researched the legal structure of companies and organizations: headquarters, divisions, subsidiaries, branches, governmental and bureaucratic entities, etc. in order to properly map sites and maintain accurate hierarchy in database.
- Met daily/weekly metrics goals.
- Liaised with and resolved issues from other departments.
- Reviewed and performed quality control audits monthly on the work of colleagues within our department.
- Performed QA testing of database, provided test results.

Education / Certificates

University of California, San Diego - Biology Ohio State University, Columbus - Art New York, NY- Business Data Processing